HITESH BHATIA

New Delhi, India

+91 9871983559

https://www.linkedin.com/in/hiteshbhatia3559

hiteshbhatia3559@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Full time professional high frequency trader in the global Cryptocurrency markets, with an in depth understanding and experience analyzing tick by tick data. Intensive experience in strategy and order execution analysis using large data sets in Python, and implementation of strategies in C++ using propreitary infrastructure.

Currently a part of the Quant effort at FalconX, with focus centric around propreitary market making, and prior experience of managing prop trading strategies which were a combination of HFT delta neutral statistical arbitrage, cross exchange derivatives arbitrage and futures strategies deployed to the cryptocurrency derivatives markets.

Dabbling with Rust and Solidity on the side to enable automated trading on DEXes in the future, on Solana and Eth-based platforms.

WORK EXPERIENCE

QUANTITATIVE TRADER

FALCONX BANGALORE

Apr 2021 - Present

QUANTITATIVE TRADER

Jan 2020 - March 2021

SMC GLOBAL SECURITIES NEW DELHI

Designing and writing strategies in C++ with proprietory libraries developed in house

Analysing data in execution flow, strategy performance, latency statistics and risk, with vanilla Python and visualisation in Jupyter Notebooks using Matplotlib/Plotly

Designing a novel cryptocurrency derivatives trading desk in a large brokerage in order to deploy proprietory pre-existing strategies Managing development of Market Data and Order Management System with two software developers on rotaation Managing communication with partners as a SPOC for SMC to cryptocurrency exchanges

QUANTITATIVE ANALYST

March 2019 - Jan 2020

IRAGE CAPITAL MUMBAI

Scrutinizing high frequency tick by tick data programmatically, and generating analysis and improvements for existing delta-1 strategies.

Traded a large variety of the Indian markets, primarily commodities (MCX) and Currencies (USDINR on NSE and BSE)

Developed Quality-of-life programs that automatically analyze data on a periodic basis, removing the need for manual analysis. Hands-on experience in Pandas for analysis and other libraries for data manipulation and transportation for automatic trade and data

DESIGNATED PARTNER

Nov 2018 - March 2019

POINT FIVE CAPITAL NEW DELHI

Handled existing and onboarding new clients, raising INR 5M of funding

Developed manual profitable futures and options strategies Automated existing strategies, deployed to the Crypto market Closed due to regulatory issues

(still manging personal wealth on these strategies)

CYBER SECURITY ANALYST

TY ANALYST ERNST & YOUNG LLP AEROCITY

June 2018 - Oct' 2018

Designed, wrote and deployed a Python based script called Auto-sqlmap

Deployed to NIC-SOC, the center point of all government internet traffic in New Delhi

Designed and wrote a Thought Leadership around the Cryptocurrency space

EDUCATION

B. TECH - IT - 71%

ADGITM

Aug' 2014 - Aug' 2018

GGSIP University, New Delhi

OTHER INTERESTS

HOBBIES

Military flight simulation and RTS gaming enthusiast Graphic Designing with competency in Adobe Photoshop Over 50 awards in Model UN and conventional debating Amateur motorcycle touring with over 15000 kms covered touring North India

PERSONAL PROJECTS

CROSS EXCHANGE ARBITRAGE

Statistical leveraged arbitrage between two cryptocurrency derivatives exchanges Using Python (Redis, ccxt, websockets) Deployed to a Linux remote server 0.5ms tick latency, 0.8ms order execution time Seperate modules for data collection, risk controls, and quote based order sizing and strategy logic Orderbook resolution using orderbook deltas ROI - 3-4% per month, ROI to 2018 - 53%

CALENDAR SPREAD

High frequency calendar spread trading capturing backwardation and 3σ contango. Predefined high/low threshold values with bollinger-band based extremity capture.

Similar network parameters and modules as above ROI - 11-15% per month, ROI to date 114%

MOMENTUM STAT ARB

A work in progress project that aims to capture correlated moves in futures with symmetric underlyings in the same market. The current system is a Delta One strategy, but may be extrapolated to the options market.

EXPANSION TO DEX TRADING

A work in progress idea that expands the above strategies to incorporate CLOB analogous DEXes (such as Mango markets and more generally Serum, DYDX etc.) to quote on and hedge against.

TECHNOLOGIES USED

C++/C#

Two years of experience in writing strategies and studies on top of existing boilerplate templates on various libraries. Deriving and capturing insights about orderbook arrival rates and their effects on the market

PYTHON

Three years of experience, intermediate level competency. Libraries used- Pandas, Matplotlib, ta-lib, ccxt, redis, numpy, exchange libs like binance_f, Dash, Panels, AWS apis

PINESCRIPT tradingview platform

Time series analysis, signals, alerts and indicators

ADOBE PHOTOSHOP

Six years of practical designing, with hundreds of logos and posters design for freelance sales

LINUX

Operational understanding of linux file systems, commands and basic awk scripting (aided with command-line python), rudimentary understanding of Kubenetes

SOLIDITY AND RUST

Very superficial understanding, working on integrating strategies with on chain metrics and trading on DEXes in my personal time

LINKS

Trading View: https://www.tradingview.com/u/hiteshbhatia3559/#published-charts GitHub: https://github.com/hiteshbhatia3559 Link to the design of this Resume https://github.com/hiteshbhatia3559/Resume